Guide to the Roger W. Moss Collection of Manuscript, Original Art and Printed Material by and about Richard Shirley Smith
Yale Center for British Art, Rare Books and Manuscripts
- Books and Articles on Richard Shirley Smith, Series I
  - The Wood Engravings of Richard Shirley Smith. Cambridge: Silent Books, 1994., Shirley Smith, Richard; Pp. [i-iv] [1-6] 7-72 [73-76]; 280 x 203 mm (Volume Moss no. 21)
    Included here is a catalogue of the engravings 1960 to 1989, a listing of exhibitions, illustrated books, and illustrated periodical & newspaper articles. Bain also assigned the numbers to Shirley Smith's wood engravings that are used throughout this checklist. However, several early engravings are omitted from Bain's list. See engravings list (Section IV).
  - The Wood Engravings of Richard Shirley Smith. Cambridge: Silent Books, 1994., Bain, Iain; Pp. [i-iv] [1-6] 7-72 [73-76]; 275 x 200 mm (Volume Moss no. 22)
    Trade paperback edition of above.
  - "Still Life with Marble Foot." The Ashmolean 33 (Christmas, 1997), Lowe, Ian; Pp. 20-21; 25 cm (Volume Moss no. 23)
    Report on the acquisition of Shirley Smith's acrylic painting of that name commissioned in honor of Anne Stevens's service to the museum. The Ashmolean Museum of Art and Archaeology in Oxford has also acquired a complete set of Shirley Smith's wood engravings.
  - Folio 50. A Bibliography of The Folio Society 1947-1996 compiled by Paul W. Nash with essays by Sue Bradbury, Valerie Grove, Frank Delaney, Robertson Davies, Douglas Martin, Charles Ede, Quentin Blake, Roderick Cave and Paul W. Nash. London: The Folio Press, 1997, in association with The British Library., Nash, Paul W.; Pp. [1-7] 8-331 [332-336]; 286 x 185 mm (Volume Moss no. 24)
    Typeset in Monotype Postscript Bembo by The Folio Society. Text printed at St Edmundsbury Press, Bury St Edmunds, on Hamilton Wove paper. Color plates printed at Barwell Colourprint, Midsomer Norton, on Sovereign Matt Cartridge paper. Bound in blue-gray book cloth at Hunter & Foulis, Edinburgh. Slipcase collage by Paul W. Nash. Richard Shirley Smith illustrated five books for The Folio Society prior to 1996, including Sir Richard de Coverly (1967) [no. 233; page 129]; Philip Stanhope (1973) [no. 327; page 152]; Robert Browning, Dramatic Monologues (1991) [no. 689; page 240]; Perfect and Imperfect Enjoyments (1992) [no. 725; page 252]; and Ovid, Metamorphoses (1995) [no. 812; page 275]. In each instance the citation in Folio 50 is accompanied by a reproduction of one Shirley Smith illustration for the book, including a full page from the Ovid on page 277. Shirley Smith subsequently contributed to four books for The Folio Society: prints for The Folio Golden Treasury designed by Simon Brett (1997); cover designs for Shakespeare, Complete Plays (1997); frontispiece and 21 line drawings for Virgil, The Ecologues (2000); and cover design for Carcopino, Daily Life in Ancient Rome (2004).
  - "Living National Treasures: Bookplate Artists." Country Life (January 7, 1999), De Moubray, Amici; p. 51 (Volume Moss no. 25)
    Photograph of Richard Shirley Smith in his studio surrounded by examples of his bookplates.
    Amicia de Moubray comments that Shirley Smith's bookplates have a 'delicate 18th -century Rococo quality, reminiscent of Rex Whistler…they often incorporate scrolls, volutes, coats of arms and delicately drawn vegetation. Primarily an artist known for murals, paintings and illustrations, Mr. Shirley Smith has been designing bookplates for more than 30 years.'
  - Richard Shirley Smith. Exhibition catalogue for Chris Beetles, Ltd., 8 & 10 Ryder Street, St James's, London, 1999., Chris Beetles Limited; Pp. [1-16]; 225 x 170 mm (Volume Moss no. 26)
    Twenty-six paintings and wood engravings illustrated (some in color) from the eighty-three items for sale. Includes essay by David Wootton, 'Richard Shirley Smith: Classic–Romantic Artist–Craftsman' and 'Richard Shirley Smith: a Selective Chronology.' Stapled soft binding.
  - Recent Acquisitions 1998. Harrow, Middlesex: Old Speech Room Gallery, Harrow School, 1999., Leder, Carolyn; Pp. [1-2] 3-52; 298 x 210 mm (Volume Moss no. 27)
    Color cover reproduction of 'Archaeological Fragments' (1986 acrylic painting; item 40 in the catalogue). Detailed discussion of items nos. 25-45 by Richard Shirley Smith purchased for Harrow School collection. Stapled soft binding. Shirley Smith attended Harrow School, 1949-1954.
  - The Paintings & Collages, 1957 to 2000. Preface by Roy Strong. London: John Murray in association with Studio House, 2002., Shirley Smith, Richard; Pp. [i-v] vi-x [1] 2-148 [149-150]; 295 x 230 mm (Volume Moss no. 28)
    Limited edition of 140 copies signed and numbered by Shirley Smith of which this is copy no. 82. Contained in a chemise are two wood engravings dating to 1961 signed and numbered by Shirley Smith: 'A Winter Night' and 'The Dark Tower,' both of which were first published in A Point of Departure by Joyce Finzi [Bain nos. 13 and 23]. Quarter bound in dark gray book cloth with decoratively printed boards and a light gray cloth-covered slipcase. Three items laid in: color prospectus for the publication; limited edition order form; and special pre-publication order form with note on verso to Roger W. Moss from Shirley Smith concerning the satisfactory reproduction of two acrylic paintings from his collection reproduced in the book.
    Sir Roy Strong remarks, 'Shirley Smith's wood engravings fit neatly into the world of Rex Whistler and Reynolds Stone, and are quite as fine as anything produced by either of them. The bookplates make a distinguished contribution to that genre: delightful masterpieces in miniature, deploying his usual architectural repertory of urns, altars and fragments of friezes through and over which sprout greenery and flowers.'
  - The Paintings & Collages, 1957 to 2000 [trade copy of the above in dust jacket], 2002; Shirley Smith, Richard; Pp. [i-v] vi-x [1] 2-148 [149-150]; 295 x 230 mm (Volume Moss no. 29)
    Inscribed 'for Gail & Roger / Richard Shirley Smith 4 April mmii.'
    While most important for its reproductions of Shirley Smith's paintings and collages and his carefully compiled list of 281 framed and three-dimensional works, this book also contains a useful chronology of his personal life and professional career up to 2000. Also listed are the main exhibitions, trompe l'oeil mural decorations, periodical articles, and illustrated reference books—many of which are included in this checklist. However, the list of illustrated books is incomplete due mainly to Shirley Smith's modestly concerning the journeywork of his early career.
    This copy retained by donor. A record for this item is also available in the Yale University Library Catalog.
  - "Richard Shirley Smith: The Paintings and Collages, 1957-2000." Parenthesis. Journal of The Fine Press Book Association 8 (June 2003), Graham, Rigby, 1931-; p. 34; 30 cm (Volume Moss no. 30)
    Book review reproducing 'Este Tomb' from Messer Pietro Mio [1985, Bain no. 278].
  - "Richard Shirley Smith: The Paintings and Collages, 1957-2000." Finzi Friends Newsletter 20 (Summer, 2002), Dale Roberts, Jeremy, 1934-; Pp. 15-17; 21 cm (Volume Moss no. 31)
    Book review reproducing 'Two Fantastics' (1984, Bain no. 283) and the acrylic painting 'Rehearsal, Trophy with Dancers' (1995).
  - "Richard Shirley Smith: The Paintings and Collages, 1957-2000." Harrow Record (2003), Lemmon, Jeremy; Pp. 32-33; 32 cm (Volume Moss no. 32)
    Book review reproducing 'Pulcinella Visits Egypt' (acrylic, 1999), 'Scales & Pears' (acrylic, 1994), and 'Venus, Candle & Bowl' (acrylic, 1998).
  - Richard Shirley Smith. Harrow, Middlesex: Old Speech Room Gallery, Harrow School, 14 February-5 May, 2003., Leder, Carolyn (Volume Moss no. 33)
    Exhibition catalogue with line-drawn cover by Shirley Smith and reproductions of two wood engravings: 'Churchyard' [1977, Bain no. 240] and bookplate for Benoît Junod [1983, Bain no. 256, North Lee no. 25]. Stapled soft cover. Laid in is Shirley Smith's article from Harrow: Portrait of an English School (London: Farringdon House, 2004) on Maurice Percival, Harrow Art Master, 1945-1954, who greatly influenced Shirley Smith.
    Old Harrovian Shirley Smith was honored with a one-man exhibition of his paintings, engravings, designs for books and cartoons for mural decorations. Exhibition curator, Carolyn Leder, wrote the introduction.
  - Book Typography: A Designer's Manual. Marlborough, Wiltshire: Libanus Press, 2005., Mitchell, Michael, 1939-; [i-x] xi [xii] 1-434; 232 x 185 mm (Volume Moss no. 34)
    Designed and typeset primarily in Albertina at Libanus Press, printed by Butler & Tanner Ltd, Frome, Somerset. Several Shirley Smith paintings used as layouts. 174, 356-361, 394. Perfect bound soft cover.
  - Contemporary World Ex Libris. Philadelphia: The Athenæum of Philadelphia, 2006., American Society of Bookplate Collectors and Designers; Pp. [1-2] i-v [1-2] 3-56 [57-58]; 248 x 177 mm (Volume Moss no. 35)
    Includes reproductions of four bookplates by Richard Shirley Smith: James Wilson/Giacomo Casanova [1999, North Lee no. 52]; Roger Cortesi/Boston Athenæum [1997, North Lee no. 50]; Nicholas Fisher [1996, North Lee no. 46] as well as the Shirley Smith book plate for the Roger W. Moss Book Fund at The Athenæum of Philadelphia [2000, North Lee no. 59] reproduced on front cover. Printed for the American Society of Bookplate Collectors and Designers exhibition at The Athenæum of Philadelphia, September-October, 2006. Stapled soft binding. A flyer on Athenæum book funds laid in.
  - Press A Bibliography 1972-2007. Chestnut Press, 2007., Askam, Mark; Pp. [1-3] 4-84; 297 x 210 mm (Volume Moss no. 36)
    Perfect bound soft cover. Inscribed by Mark Askam on the half title: 'To Richard [Shirley Smith] Love the engravings! Mark / 2nd proof edition (1 of 4 copies) This is an early reading proof––produced digitally of an as-yet-unfinished bibliography. It is not likely to get published in a hard-copy form, but is available as an internet resource.'
    Richard Shirley Smith engravings illustrated three books for Anthony Baker's Gruffyground Press: James Reeves, The Closed Door (1976-77) nos. 5a and 5b; Six Hampshire Epitaphs (1978) nos. 6a and 6b; and John Heath-Stubbs, Buzz Buzz (1981) nos. 12a and 12b. Shirley Smith's engravings for Reeves and Heath-Stubbs are reproduced. 41 & 42. Several limited editions of Shirley Smith's engravings were also produced by Gruffyground Press: two editions of the engraving used for The Closed Door [Bain no. 239] (sixty strikes in all); two editions of the engraving used for Six Hampshire Epitaphs [Bain no.240] (one hundred strikes in all); and one edition of the engraving used for Buzz Buzz [Bain no. 251] (one hundred strikes in all). There was also a special run of The Closed Door engraving which Anthony Baker sent out as a Christmas greeting and a postcard version of the same engraving run by Michael Mitchell at the Libanus Press. Mitchell also printed the Buzz Buzz engraving as a Christmas greeting.
  - The Gruffyground Press: A Bibliography. Hitchin, Hertfordshire, Chestnut Editions, 2011., Askam, Mark; Pp. [1-3] 4-94 [95-96]; 297 x 210 mm (Volume Moss no. 36a)
    Inscribed 'For Roger Moss with best wishes Mark (Askam)' Following the Libanus Press publication of this checklist, Mark Askam sent RWM this copy of the enlarged edition supported by the Arts Council of Great Britain.
  - The Clock of the Years. An Anthology of Writings on Gerald and Joy Finzi¸ Marking Twenty-Five Years of the Finzi Friends Newsletter. Foreword by Paul Spicer. Lichfield: Chosen Press, 2007., Jordan, Rolf; Pp. [i-x] xi-xx [1] 2-199 [200]; 240 x 165 mm (Volume Moss no. 37)
    Typeset by Rolf Jordan in Linotype Janson and printed by Cromwell Press, Trowbridgem Wiltshire. Bound in dark red book cloth with dust jacket.
    Richard Shirley Smith's long association with the Finzi family is commemorated here by the use of his 1961 wood engravings first published in Joy Finzi's A Point of Departure (1967) which are reproduced on pages 90, 92, 94, 97, 100, 102 and 220. Also included in this anthology is a reprint of Jeremy Dale Roberts's review of Shirley Smith's The Paintings and Collages which originally appeared in the Finzi Friends Newsletter [item 31 above]. Laid in are photocopies of the obituaries of Joy Finzi from The Telegraph (June 6, 1991), The Guardian (June 19, 1991), and Shirley Smith's reminiscences of her from Joy Finzi, 1907-1991: Tributes from her friends.
  - "Wood–engraved Bookplates." Offprint from Matrix 27 (pages 76-81 in paper wrappers). The Whittington Press, 2007., Shirley Smith, Richard (Volume Moss no. 38)
    Seven of Shirley Smith's bookplates reproduced: Brian North Lee [1984, Bain no. 259, North Lee no.26] Benoît Junod [1983, Bain no. 256, North Lee no. 25], Adrian Sassoon [1980, Bain no. 248, North Lee no. 20], Anne Stevens [1983, Bain no. 255, North Lee no.24], Ian Bain [1983, Bain no. 253, North Lee no.22], and David J. Profumo [1984, Bain no. 365, North Lee no. 30], Sir John Sykes [1996, North Lee no.48]. Inscribed 'for Roger Moss…Richard Shirley Smith.'
- Publications Designed or Illustrated by Richard Shirley Smith, Series II
  - When April Came. Suite of Five Songs for Chorus and Piano. London: Novello & Company, Ltd., 1962., Burtch, Mervyn (Volume Moss no. 39)
    Richard Shirley Smith gave Roger W. Moss a copy of the cover he designed; a complete score has not been located or examined. This cover is based on an enlargement of Shirley Smith's wood engraving 'Vines' [Bain no. 10].
  - Golden Cantata. Poems by Kathleen Raine, London: Novello & Company, Ltd., 1963., Bliss, Arthur, 1891-1975; Pp. [i-vi] [1] 2-54; 247 x 172 mm (Volume Moss no. 40)
    Richard Shirley Smith designed the cover. Stapled soft binding.
  - The Water and the Fire. A dramatic oratorio in four scenes for soprano, tenor & baritone soli, chorus and orchestra (Opus 16). London: Novello & Company, Ltd., 1963., Milner, Anthony; Pp. [i-viii] [1] 2-120; 247 x 170 mm (Volume Moss no. 41)
    Richard Shirley Smith designed the cover. Perfect bound soft binding. Christmas card from Anthony Milner laid in together with programs for Milner's 60th birthday concert at St John's, Smith Square, London, May 12, 1985, and the performance of The Water and the Fire at Royal Festival Hall, May 19, 1980.
  - Toy Cupboard Songs for Use in Nursery & Infant Schools. Accompaniment for Piano, Percussion & Chime. Borough Green, Sevenoaks, Kent: Novello & Company, Ltd., 1963., Rees, Olive; Pp. [i-ii] [1] 2-13[14]; 150 x 232 mm (Volume Moss no. 42)
  - Leaves of Life. A Ballad-Cantata. Commissioned by Mrs. Susan Philipson-Stow for the Farham Festival. London: Novello Company, Ltd., 1963., Joubert, John, 1927-; Pp. [¬i-ii] [1] 2-58; 244 x 170 mm (Volume Moss no. 43)
    'Cover design by Richard Shirley Smith'. This copy inscribed on the title page 'Greetings from John'. Perfect bound soft binding.
  - Urbs Beata. A Cantata for Tenor & Baritone Soli. Commissioned on the occasion of the completion of St George's Cathedral, Cape Town, by the Association of Friends of the Cathedral. London: Novello Company, Ltd., 1963., Joubert, John, 1927-; Pp. [i-ii] [1] 2-78; 247 x 170 mm (Volume Moss no. 44)
    'Cover design by Richard Shirley Smith'. This copy inscribed on the title page 'Howard—with greetings from John'. Perfect bound soft binding.
  - The Holy Mountain. A Canticle for SATB Chorus and Two Pianos, Opus 44. London: Novello & Company, Ltd., 1964., Joubert, John, 1927-; Pp. [i-ii] [1] 2-21[22]; 247 x 173 mm (Volume Moss no. 45)
    Richard Shirley Smith designed the cover. This copy inscribed on the title page 'with best wishes' by the composer. Stapled soft binding.
    In 1963 Shirley Smith began illustrating books for the London publishers Longmans, Green and Company; Hamish Hamilton; Burns & Oates; Faber and Faber; Andre Deutsch; Denis Dobson, as well as Oxford University Press.
  - Of Flowers & A Village: An Entertainment for Flower Lovers. London: Hamish Hamilton, 1963. Printed by Western Printing Services, Bristol. First edition., Blunt, Wilfrid, 1901-1987; Pp. [i-xi] xii-xv, 1–296; (203 x 140 mm) (Volume Moss no. 46)
    'Illustrations and jacket design by Richard Shirley Smith' consisting of fifty line drawings including the dust jacket. Bound in green book cloth with dust jacket.
  - Characters. Translated by Henri Van Laun; introduction by Denys C. Potts. London: Oxford University Press, 1963., La Bruyère, Jean de, 1645-1696; Pp. [i-vi] vii-xi [1] 2-321 [322-324]; 190 x 130 mm (Volume Moss no. 47)
    'Jacket illustration [line drawing] by Richard Shirley Smith'. Bound in teal book cloth with dust jacket.
  - The Great Teresa. London: Burns & Oates, 1963., Hamilton, Elizabeth, 1906-; Pp. [1-12] 13-190 [191-192]; 180 x 112 mm (Volume Moss no. 48)
    'The engraving on the front cover is by Richard Shirley-Smith' [portrait of St Teresa of Avila; Bain no. 39]. Perfect bound paperback.
  - Pandora's Last Voyage. London: Longman, Green and Co., Ltd., 1963., Geoffrey, Rawson; Pp. [i-v] vi-vii [viii-x] [1-2] 3-165 [166]; 223 x 145 mm (Volume Moss no. 49)
    Printed by Jarrold and Sons, Ltd., Norwich. First edition. 'Wood engraving by Richard Shirley Smith' [Bain no. 40]. Bound in light blue book cloth with dust jacket.
  - The English Church 1000 to 1060 A Constitutional History. London: Longmans, Green and Company, Ltd., 1963., Barlow, Frank; Pp. [i-vi] vii-xii [1] 2–324; 230 x 155 mm (Volume Moss no. 50)
    Printed at the University Press, Aberdeen. First edition. 'Jacket illustration from wood-engraving by Richard Shirley Smith of pastoral staff in the Victoria and Albert Museum' [Bain no. 41]. Bound in pale olive-green book cloth with dust jacket.
  - The Writings of St Francis of Assisi. Translated by Benen Fahy, O.F.M, with Introduction and Notes by Placid Hermann, O. F.M. London: Burns and Oates, Ltd., 1963., Francis, Saint, of Assisi, 1182-1226; Pp. [1-4] 5-200; 222 x 145 mm (Volume Moss no. 51)
    Printed by Ditchling Press, Ltd., Ditchling, Hassocks, Sussex. 'The engraving on the jacket is by Richard Shirley Smith' [portrait of St. Francis; Bain no. 43]. Bound in red book cloth with dust jacket.
  - The Gourmet's Garden. London: Faber and Faber, Ltd., 1964., Bartrúm, Douglas; Pp. [1-8] 9-248; 222 x 145 mm (Volume Moss no. 52)
    Printed by Latimer Trend & Company, Ltd., Plymouth. First edition. 'With decorations by Richard Shirley-Smith' consisting of ten wood engravings [Bain nos. 44-53] used in various combinations on dust jacket, title page, and chapter heads. Bound in orange book cloth with dust jacket. This set of engravings would be reprinted in a limited edition in 1985, see entry no. 116.
    Faber and Faber was the first commercial publisher fully to exploit the illustrative potential of Shirley Smith's wood engravings, as demonstrated by Bartrúm's Gourmet's Garden [entry no. 52] and Clark's The Darkening Green [entry no. 54].
  - A Street in Suffolk. London: Faber and Faber, 1964., Bell, Adrian, 1901-1980; Pp. [8] 170; 225 x 142 mm (Volume Moss no. 52a)
    "With drawings by Richard Shirley Smith" (monotype and line drawings). Printed by Ebenezer Baylis and Son Limited The Trinity Press, Worcester and London. Dust Jacket and internal drawings.
  - To Any Christian: Letters from the Saints Selected and Arranged by A Benedictine of Stanbrook. London: Burns & Oates, Ltd., 1964., Benedictine, of Stanbrook Abbey; Pp. [i-iv] v-ix [x] 1-299 [300]; 222 x 145 mm (Volume Moss no. 53)
    Printed by Spottiswoode, Ballantyn & Company, Ltd. First edition. With no mention of Richard Shirley Smith but four of his engravings [Bain nos. 54-57] used for dust jacket, title page and section heads in various combinations. Bound in blue book cloth with dust jacket.
  - The Darkening Green. London: Faber and Faber, Ltd., 1964., Clarke, Elizabeth; Pp. [1-10] 11-237 [238]; 205 x 145 mm (Volume Moss no. 54)
    First edition. Printed by Bowering Press, Plymouth. 'The decorations in this book were engraved on wood by Richard Shirley–Smith.' Ten engravings used on dust jacket, title page and chapter heads in various combinations [Bain nos. 58–67]. Bound in light blue book cloth with dust jacket.
  - A Tale of Two Cities. Appendixes and notes by D. K. Swan. London: Longmans, Green and Co., Ltd., 1964., Dickens, Charles, 1812-1870; Pp. [i-viii] [1-3] 4-533 [534]; 181 x 110 mm (Volume Moss no. 55)
    Printed by Hazell Watson and Viney, Ltd., Aylesbury, Bucks. Maps of London and Paris by Richard Shirley Smith. viii–ix; illustrated with four line drawings of standing male figures. Perfect bound trade paperback.
  - Adam Bede. Longmans, Green and Co., Ltd., c. 1964., Eliot, George, 1819-1880 (Volume Moss no. 56)
    Richard Shirley Smith recalls he designed this Longmans paperback cover, no additional information available; complete copy not located or examined.
  - Water & Life. New York: Atheneum, 1964, Milne, Lorus Johnson, 1912-; Pp. [i-x] [1-2] 3-275 [276-278]; 218 x 145 mm (Volume Moss. no 57)
    First edition. Published in Canada by McClelland & Stewart, Ltd. Composition by Clarke & Way, New York, printed by Halliday Lithograph Corp., West Hanover, Massachusetts and bound by H. Wolff, New York. This copy of Water & Life was sent to Shirley Smith by the London publisher Andre Deutsch with the commission to design a new dust jacket for a contemplated British edition. Shirley Smith's design was printed in proof and he put it on this copy of the New York edition. The Deutsch edition was never released. 'Jacket design by Richard Shirley-Smith.' Shirley Smith's copy with his studio library ex libris.
  - Helmet and Wasps. London: Andre Deutsch, 1964., Mott, Michael, 1930-; Pp. [1-6] 7-190 [191-192]; 203 x 136 mm (Volume Moss no. 58)
    First edition. Printed by Ebenezer Baylis and Son, Ltd., Worcester and London. 'Jacket design by Richard Shirley-Smith' [Bain no. 68]. Bound in yellow book cloth with dust jacket.
  - The Trial of St. Thomas More. London: Burns & Oates, Ltd., 1964., Reynolds, Ernest Edwin, 1894-; Pp. [i-viii] ix-xiv, 1-169 [170]; 222 x 147 mm (Volume Moss no. 59)
    Printed in Monotype Bembo by W. & J. Mackay & Co., Ltd.; simultaneously published in New York by Kennedy and in Montreal by Palm Publishers. 'The engraving on the jacket is by Richard Shirley–Smith' [Bain no. 70]. Bound in red book cloth with dust jacket. '
  - Thomas More and Erasmus. London: Burns & Oates, Ltd., 1965., Reynolds, Ernest Edwin, 1894-; Pp. [i-vi] vii-x, 1-260 [261-262]; 223 x 150 mm (Volume Moss no. 60)
    Simultaneously published in New York by Fordham University Press. Engraved portraits of More and Erasmus by Shirley Smith used on the dust jacket [Bain nos. 70 and 82]. Bound in red book cloth with dust jacket.
  - The Heart of Thomas More Selected Readings for Every Day of the Year. London: Burns & Oates, Ltd., 1966., Reynolds, Ernest Edwin, 1894- (Volume Moss no. 61)
    The Golden Library. Simultaneously published Springfield, Illinois, by Templegate, 1966. Here the Shirley Smith engraved portrait of More [Bain no. 70] is strikingly used on the gold dust jacket. [Dust jacket only; complete copy not examined.]
  - A Book for All Seasons Readings for Every Day of the Year from the Works of Thomas More. Springfield, Illinois: Templegate Publishers, 1978., Reynolds, Ernest Edwin, 1894-; Pp. [1-4] 5-178 [179-180]; 210 x 140 mm (Volume Moss no. 62)
    'Wood engraving by Richard Shirley Smith' [portrait of Sir Thomas More; Bain no. 70] here used as a frontispiece rather than on the cover. Originally this title was published as The Heart of Thomas More, London: Burns & Oates, Ltd., 1966.
  - A Love Affair. London: Andre Deutsch, Ltd., 1965., Buzzati, Dino, 1906-1972; Pp. [i-iv] [1-2] 3-299 [300]; 205 x 140 mm (Volume Moss no. 63)